# Paul Thomas O'Riordan

I am a highly dedicated and adaptable professional with a strong work ethic. I have extensive experience in teaching (10 years) as well as leadership, training, coaching, and managing people from a wide range of backgrounds and have consistently proven my capacity to bring people together and work well as a team. I am an excellent communicator with an astute ability to identify what excites and motivates people.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

## 2019-present

# PHYSICAL EDUCATION TEACHER & HEAD OF YEAR

- Hastings British School, Madrid, Spain
  - + Designed and delivered developmentally appropriate learning experiences for students aged 11-17 to reach standards set out in the UK National curriculum. Teaching to IGCSE level with 100% pass rate with over 80% A standard.
  - + Head of Year for the year 10/11 cohort, which included pastoral guidance and support, monitoring and recording student behaviour and attendance in school, monitoring student academic and social progress, management of form tutors, weekly assemblies and organisation of PSHE programme. Highest parental and student satisfaction rates in the entire school.
  - + Additional responsibilities included organisation of school wide events such as sports tournaments, ski trips, shows and excursions. Coaching of school basketball team competing in official Madrid sports league on weekends.

#### 2017 - 2019

# HEAD OF PHYSICAL EDUCATION DEPARTMENT & GEOGRAPHY TEACHER

- The International School of Madrid, Madrid, Spain
  - + Head of Physical Education Department. Coordinating all teaching and learning, planning and achieving standards set out in the UK National curriculum
  - + Head of school "House Programme" which includes organisation of school wide events such as sports tournaments, ski trips, shows and excursions

#### 2016, 2017, 2018

## **CENTRE MANAGER**

- MLI International Schools, Wembley, London, UK
  - + Oversaw the successful running of 3 consecutive summer schools with a yearly turnover of over 800 international students
  - + Managed teams of 30-40 staff including educators and monitors each year
  - + Liaised with local partners for accommodation, catering and transport
  - + Responsible for staff induction training and continuous professional development
  - + Produced the highest revenue and highest customer satisfaction levels of all 6 summer centres for 3 consecutive years

## 2016-2017

#### HEAD OF PHYSICAL EDUCATION DEPARTMENT

- The Academy International School, Marratxí, Mallorca, Spain
  - + Head of Physical Education Department. Designed developmentally appropriate learning experiences for students aged 4-17 to reach standards set out in the UK National curriculum. Teaching to IGCSE level with 100% pass rate with over 80% distinction rate

#### 2014-2016

## PHYSICAL EDUCATION TEACHER

- IES Juan Gris (Secondary College, Spanish curriculum), Mostoles, Madrid, Spain
  - + Planned and delivered the Spanish Physical Education National Curriculum through English with an over 80% pass rate in Bachillerato
  - + Collaborated with the bilingual department on curriculum development

#### 2014, 2015

## **ACTIVITIES COORDINATOR**

- MLI International Schools, Edinburgh, UK
  - + Successfully implemented the summer activities and excursions programme for 2 consecutive summer schools with a turnover of over 400 international students each year.
  - + Managed, rostered and motivated a group of 15-20 monitors.

#### 2012-2014

## PHYSICAL EDUCATION & GEOGRAPHY TEACHER

- O'Carolan College, Nobber, Meath, Ireland
  - + Designed and delivered developmentally appropriate learning experiences for students aged 12-18 to reach standards set out in the Irish National curriculum in both Physical Education and Geography.
  - + Guided a cohort of Leaving Cert Applied students through the leisure and recreation course with 100% pass rate and 65% distinction.
  - + Additional responsibilities included: Head of Year (TY), Coach of school football and basketball teams, delivering speech and language therapy sessions in the schools Specialist Autism Centre.

## 2011-2012

## PHYSICAL EDUCATION & GEOGRAPHY TEACHER

- Scoil Uí Mhuire, Dunleer, Louth, Ireland (Maternity Cover)
  - + Designed and delivered developmentally appropriate learning experiences for students aged 12-18 to reach standards set out in the Irish National curriculum in both Physical Education and Geography. Guided a cohort of Leaving Cert Applied students through the leisure and recreation course with 100% pass rate and 65% distinction.

#### 2010 - present

## PERSONAL TRAINER, COACH, SWIM INSTRUCTOR

# **LANGUAGES**









FRUCATION	
EDUCATION	
0011	POST CRADUATE DIRICATA IN EDUCATION
2011	POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA IN EDUCATION
0010	- University of Limerick, County Limerick, Republic of Ireland
2010	BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN PHYSICAL EDUCATION STUDIES
0004	– Munster Technological University, Tralee, County Kerry, Republic of Ireland
2004	LEAVING CERTIFICATE
	- C.B.S. Tralee, County Kerry, Republic of Ireland
CPD	CONTINUING PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT COURSES INCLUDING
	<ul> <li>Outstanding leadership for new and aspiring leaders via Acade (NABBS 2021)</li> </ul>
	- Building learning power in students with author Graham Powell (2019 & 2020)
	- Mindfulness for wellbeing and peak performance via FutureLearn (2020)
	- Growth Mindset in schools (2018)
	- PSHE (2019), Basketball (2014), Gymnastics (2014), Occupational therapy (2013), Speech
	& Language therapy (2013)
SKILLS	
Advanced	MICROSOFT OFFICE, PAGES, NUMBERS, KEYNOTE, GOOGLE SUITE
Intermediate	ADOBE PHOTOSHOP, HTML, MOVIE EDITING SOFTWARE
ADDITIONAL	
	- EQF ACCREDITED PERSONAL TRAINER (2010)
	- RED CROSS FIRST AID QUALIFIED (2017)
	- QUALIFIED LIFEGUARD (2008)
INTERESTS	
	- PREVIOUS HEAD COACH OF F.C. BRITANICO DE MADRID
	(6TH TIER OF SPANISH FOOTBALL)
	- PREVIOUS HEAD COACH OF IRISH NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP
	WINNING BASKETBALL TEAMS
	- PLAYING: IRISH BASKETBALL NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP WINNER
	- VOLUNTEERING: SPECIAL OLYMPICS IRELAND
	- TRAVEL ENTHUSIAST
	- MUSIC LOVER
	- SPORTS AND NUTRITION
	- SNOWBOARD, SURF & SKATE
DEFENENCES	
REFERENCES	

# **AVAILABLE ON REQUEST**